It's nothing serious. She just got drunk.
无妨 醉酒而已
Drunk?
醉酒
The Third Princess had never been intoxicated
三公主平日里
no matter how much she drank.
那可是千杯不醉呀
But one alcoholic drink intoxicated her yesterday.
昨日怎么会一杯就倒
It couldn't have happened.
这绝不可能
Your Highness, you are awake.
三公主 你醒了
Why is the dream still not over?
这梦怎么还没做完啊
But... But...
不 不
Why is it still not over?
怎么还没做完啊
Did Han Shuo change the poisoned drink?
难道是韩烁把毒酒换了
Actors nowadays
不是 现在
don't even consult the screenwriter
演员改剧本
before revising the screenplay?
都不跟编剧商量的吗
How can I go back now?
那我怎么才回得去啊
No. No.
不行 不行
Too much pain. Too much pain.
太疼了 太疼了
Too ugly. Too ugly.
太丑了 太丑了
Xiaoqian,
千儿啊
everyone dies eventually.
人固有一死
Death is not scary.
死不可怕
What's scary is
可怕的是
the filming will start soon and you haven't submitted the screenplay.
都开机了 你还没交稿呢
It's so scary.
太可怕了
What if dying in the dream
万一梦里的死
means dying from overwork in the real world?
就是现实中的过劳死呢
I'd like to thank Han Shuo
感谢韩烁
and the actors who improvised.
感谢临场发挥的演员
Thank them for giving a young screenwriter
给了一个年轻编剧
the chance to learn about herself.
自我认识的机会
But how can I go back?
可是我要怎么回去
Huayuan City's Second Princess Chen Chuchu
花垣城二郡主陈楚楚
has gone through hardships
历经磨难
and finally becomes the City Owner.
终于登上城主之位
At Chen Chuchu's succession ceremony,
陈楚楚继任大典上
auspicious signs occur, the sun and the moon shine at the same time,
天降祥瑞 日月同辉
heaven's door opens,
天门大开
and the sky looks splendid.
异彩漫天
Gosh.
天哪
If I have to finish this dream
如果我需要做完这场梦
in order to wake up,
才能醒过来
which means I have to see auspicious signs occur and heaven's door open,
天降异象 天门大开
then I must endure to the end of this drama.
那我岂不是要坚持到全剧终
Wait.
等等
If Han Shuo doesn't help Chuchu,
没有韩烁帮楚楚
she won't become the Crown Princess.
她怎么当上少城主呢
Han Shuo.
韩烁
Zi Rui.
梓锐
Where is Han Shuo?
韩烁呢
He is in prison,
人在天牢
waiting to be executed today.
今日问斩
-Why? -Why?
为什么 为什么
Stop counting. Just tell me.
别数了 赶紧说
Her Majesty suspects that Young Master Han has an ulterior motive for the marriage.
城主怀疑韩少君入赘另有图谋
So, she plans to use last night's incident as the excuse to...
所以要趁着昨夜的事
Spare him, mother!
刀下留人 母亲
...remove the bad seed.
斩草除根
Your Highness.
三公主
Young Master, our people are waiting outside,
少君 我们的人已经候在外面了
ready to rescue us.
随时救我们出去
As for the plan to seize the Dragon Bone...
只是取得龙骨的计划
Tell them
吩咐下去
to light the beacon tonight.
今晚就点燃狼烟
The Xuanhu City Guards will march southward
明日玄虎护城军南下
and occupy Huayuan tomorrow.
攻占花垣
Young Master, you should think twice.
少君 三思啊
The Dragon Bone...
这龙骨
Forget the Dragon Bone.
龙骨不要了
Before I could obtain the Dragon Bone,
这还没取得龙骨呢
Chen Qianqian could irritate me to death.
先就被陈芊芊给气死了
I can't wait to capture
我现在恨不得立刻
Huayuan City's Chen and her daughter.
活捉花垣陈氏母女
Chen Qianqian
陈芊芊
will be put to death
凌迟处死
after suffering from three thousand cuts.
活剐三千刀
Not one less cut.
少一刀都不行
Young Master, take it easy.
少君 您先息怒啊
As the saying goes,
俗话说得好
"A little plan spoils..."
小不谋则乱
"A little impatience spoils great plans."
小不忍则乱大谋
We can't give up the Dragon Bone
我们不能因为一个三公主
because of the Third Princess.
放弃龙骨啊
Your Majesty, the Third Princess is here to pay you respect.
禀城主 三公主来请安了
Pay me respect?
请安
More like she is here for Han Shuo.
我看她是为了韩烁吧
You are right.
城主说得是
The Third Princess...
三公主她
Mother! Mother!
母亲 母亲
Mother! Mo...
母亲 母
Mother, please release Han Shuo.
母亲 你放了韩烁吧
Mother.
母亲
Your Highness.
三公主
Young Master Han attempted to poison you on the wedding night.
韩少君新婚之夜谋害三公主
He should be executed according to the law.
问律当斩
It wasn't Young Master Han's intention
韩少君他
to poison me.
不是有意要毒害我
I wronged him.
那是我冤枉他的
You had a high alcohol tolerance.
三公主海量
You had never been drunk.
曾经千杯不醉
How come one drink intoxicated you yesterday?
为何 昨日一杯就倒啊
I...
我
When will Han Shuo be executed?
韩烁多久问斩
Three quarters past 11 o'clock.
午时三刻
What time is it now?
现在几刻
One quarter past 11 o'clock.
午时一刻
One quarter past 11 o'clock already?
午时一刻了
This is a life-and-death matter.
人命关天的事
It's one quarter past 11 o'clock
都午时一刻了
and you're asking me about my alcohol tolerance.
你还问我酒量的事
You...
你说
Enough!
放肆
Of course that is important.
当然重要了
You are my daughter, a noble lady.
你是我的女儿 千金之躯
You passing out from alcohol
莫说是醉晕过去
or losing a wisp of hair
就是少了一根头发
is an important matter,
那也是大事
not child's play.
岂可儿戏
How fierce.
好凶啊
Qianqian,
芊芊
the black stone mine
我们花垣城
has brought wealth to Huayuan City.
靠着乌石矿享受富贵
All this time,
一直以来
Xuanhu City has regarded men as superior
玄虎城都以男子为尊
and men as the people in charge.
男人就是天
It's been at daggers down with Huayuan City,
与我们花垣势不两立
coveting our black stone mine.
还对我们的乌石矿虎视眈眈
Under these circumstances,
在这种情况下
the obstinate owner of Xuanhu City
一直桀骜不驯的玄虎城城主
has proposed to marry his son off
竟主动将他唯一的儿子
into our family in Huayuan.
入赘我们花垣
What do you think?
你说
Does he mean to surrender
这是真心降服
or does he harbor an ulterior motive?
还是另有所图
Never mind.
罢了罢了
I have told you this
这种事
for numerous times.
我已经给你讲过很多遍了
If you'd been able to understand,
你要真能理解
you would have shared my worries.
早就应该替我分担
Han Shuo was supposed to marry Chuchu.
韩烁原本是要和楚楚成婚的
I didn't know you would snatch the groom in public.
没想到 被你当众抢亲
I... I...
我 我
I know I've made a mistake.
我知道错了
I'm here to apologize.
我这不是来认错的吗
Besides, he and I
再说了 我跟他
haven't worshiped heaven, gone on a parade and had a wedding.
没祭天 没游街 没拜堂
You can consider us unmarried.
你就当我们没有结过这个
Let him marry Chuchu.
你让他跟楚楚成婚去
But the whole city knows you snatched the groom.
可是全城的人都知道你抢亲了
Chuchu can't marry Han Shuo now.
楚楚还能要韩烁吗
There will be opportunities to foster the love
男女主角的情感线
between my hero and heroine later on.
后面还有办法推
Han Shuo must not die.
可韩烁一定不能死
I understand.
我明白
But he doesn't understand.
可他不明白
He?
他
Do you understand?
你能明白吗
Your Majesty.
城主
Should we find a doctor for her?
要不要 找个大夫看看
No need for a doctor.
找什么大夫
No doctor knows this kind of thing better than me.
这种事 大夫有我明白吗
Tell me. Whose baby is that?
说 谁的
I don't know.
不知道
Consider it Han Shuo's baby.
就 就当作是韩烁的吧
Nonsense!
荒唐
Han Shuo entered the city the day before yesterday
韩烁前日进城
and married you yesterday.
昨日跟你成婚
Today, you are...
今日你就
You are pregnant.
你就有了
No.
不是
You useless wretch.
你这个不成器的
At the end of the day,
说到底
Huayuan City
纵使我们花垣城
doesn't restrain women like Xuanhu City,
不像玄虎城那般约束女子
but we still have ethics and rules.
但毕竟也有礼法呀
As the daughter of Her Majesty,
你作为堂堂的城主之女
you should at least have some manners.
好歹顾及点规矩体统吧
Mother, it's two quarters past 11 o'clock.
母亲 午时二刻
Sangqi.
桑奇
Go tell Han Shuo.
你去告诉韩烁
If he is willing to acknowledge his relation with the baby,
只要他肯认下这个孩子
I will pardon him.
我就恕他无罪
Yes.
是
Go.
快
You.
你
Watch your mouth.
管好你的嘴
Before enough months pass,
在没到月份之前
you are not to reveal your pregnancy.
不许声张
(Yueli Mansion) Here is Her Majesty's decree.
城主令
According to the benevolent City Owner,
承城主慈谕
after Young Master of Xuanhu, Han Shuo
玄虎少君韩烁
got married,
自成婚以来
he has been diligent, obedient,
勤勉柔顺
and gentle,
性情温良
and he has been of service by making a baby.
传嗣有功
Therefore he is rewarded with one jade scepter,
特 赏赐玉如意一柄
one peacock feather fan,
孔雀羽扇一把
three pi of green mandarin duck silk,
鸳鸯碧波绸缎三匹
one box of green tea,
上好绿茶一盒
one pair of glazed bottles...
琉璃瓶一对
Young Master.
少君
How come all these things are green?
怎么都是绿的
...and one gilded jadeite headdress.
翡翠金冠一顶
Young Master.
少君
Take it easy.
消消气
Young Master, you must be unaware
少君有所不知
of a custom in Huayuan City.
这花垣城有一民俗
Getting a green headdress from your elder
若长辈赐于晚辈予绿冠
means your elder commends you
那 就说明长辈在夸你
for being virtuous, amiable and generous.
恪守夫德 贤良大度
Then
这么说来
I should thank Her Highness
我还得感谢三公主
for giving me a green hat. (It indicates he is a cuckold.)
送了我一顶绿帽子
Han Shuo, look on the bright side.
少君 你想开一点嘛
The baby is not yours,
这孩子虽然不是你的
but the woman is yours.
可媳妇是你的呀
Well, I also heard
这 小人听说
of a custom in Xuanhu City.
在玄虎城也有一个民俗
A man can marry many wives and concubines.
说这男子一生可娶三妻四妾
A man's wife
这妾室所生子女
should treat his concubine's child
那这原配
as her own and take care of the child.
也应视同己出 悉心照顾
It's the same in Huayuan
到了我们花垣
except a change of gender.
只不过将男子变为女子
Do you have
不知少君
any problems?
有何觉得不妥呀
Sangqi.
桑奇
You can't talk sense into him.
你跟他说不通的
Hey, the baby won't have your last name.
我说 这孩子又不跟你姓
Why are you so unhappy?
急个什么劲
Outrageous!
岂有此理
I can't believe children in Huayuan don't have their father's last name.
花垣子嗣居然不随夫姓
Refreshing, isn't it?
多新鲜啊
Let me settle accounts with you.
我给你们算笔账啊
Take me and your Young Master for example.
就拿我和你家少君为例
Whose house are you in?
现在住这房子是谁的
The Third Princess's.
三公主的呀
Who covers your daily expenses?
那日常开销花的钱是谁的
To whom do these servants belong?
这满屋子的侍从又是谁的
Who will give birth
若这孩子出生了
to the baby?
从谁的肚子里出来
Still the Third Princess.
还是三公主的呀
That settles it.
这不就得了
Your Young Master can't even help deliver the baby.
你家少君连生孩子都帮不上忙
Don't nitpick.
就不要挑三拣四了
I...
我
By the way, Your Highness,
对了 三公主
Her Majesty ordered me
城主特意吩咐小的
to bring you this.
把这个给你送来
She said you loved eating this.
说你爱吃
What is it?
什么呀
Your Highness.
三公主
Young Master.
少君
What shall we do now?
接下来我们该怎么办
Since she insists
既然她一口咬定
that I poisoned her,
是我下毒害她
I should do as she wishes.
如果不顺了她的意
Otherwise, my suffering would be for nothing.
岂不白受这场罪
Tell our people
吩咐我们的人
to take action as planned.
按原计划动手
I want neither the bastard
莫说这孽种了
nor the woman.
就是大人我也不想留
Yes.
是
Young Master.
少君
Arrangements have been made.
已经安排妥当
The glazed plate has been poisoned.
毒就下在琉璃盏内
She'll take the poison at noon and the poison will act at midnight.
中午服用 午夜发作
No one will know.
神不知鬼不觉
There are many more delicious foods today.
今天加了好多好吃的
Come on.
来 快 快 快
Hurry.
快快
According to Huayuan City's rules,
那个 按我们花垣城的规矩
when the Third Princess dines,
我们三公主用膳
you must stay to serve her
你得在旁边陪侍着
and distribute the foods for her.
替我们主子布菜
Sure.
这是自然
Young Master, the glazed plate has been poisoned.
少君 毒就下在琉璃盏内
Yong Master, the glazed plate.
少君 琉璃盏内
Yum. Yum.
好吃 好吃
Serve all the foods!
一起上
(Two hours ago) Your Highness.
公主
The kitchen staff asked what you would like to eat today.
厨房问 今天吃什么
What would I like to eat today?
吃什么
I want everything on this menu.
炒一本
And I want the best tableware.
餐具也要最好的
Yes.
是
All the plates will be replaced by glazed plates.
那就全换成琉璃盏吧
What is a glazed plate?
什么是琉璃盏
A plate that has been glazed.
用琉璃做的盏
Did Han Shuo poison the dishes?
莫非韩烁在菜里藏毒
Han Shuo, you disappoint me.
好你个韩烁
I took pains to rescue you from prison.
我辛辛苦苦将你从大牢里救出来
And you repay my kindness with enmity.
你却恩将仇报
Han Shuo, you have toiled for the whole day.
少君今天操劳一天了
You should sit down
不如坐下来
and dine with me.
陪我一起吃吧
No.
不了
According to Huayuan City's rules,
你们花垣城的规矩
men must not dine at the table.
男子不上饭桌
You should...
还是三公主
Xuanhu City has a saying,
这玄虎城有一句方言
"Follow whoever you marry."
嫁鸡随鸡 嫁狗随狗
Now that we are married,
既然我们已经是夫妻了
you should follow me.
那就应该是妇唱夫随
Han Shuo, enjoy.
少君 请用
You need to eat for two now.
你现在是一人吃两人补
You should have all the foods.
还是三公主请吧
But the guest should suit the convenience of the host.
当然是客随主便了
I'm asking you to eat. You must eat.
我让你吃你就得吃
Open your mouth.
张嘴
No. No.
不 不用
Living in harmony and showing respect to each other.
琴瑟和鸣 相敬如宾
What a loving couple.
恩爱
Nonsense.
恩爱个屁
Not in harmony.
琴瑟个头
Don't stand there.
都别愣着了呀
Prepare another meal.
赶紧重新准备
No need.
不用准备了
I'm done eating.
我不吃了
I can't eat like this.
这饭没法吃
Where are you going?
你去哪儿呀
The City Owner's mansion.
城主府
For what?
去城主府干吗呀
Food.
吃饭
I'm going with you.
那我也去吧
The glazed plate.
琉璃盏
Young Master.
少君
Bai Ji,
白芨
you know what would happen to those who betrayed me.
你知道背叛我的人什么下场
Young Master, spare me.
少君饶命啊
I dare not betray you.
属下不敢
I've always been faithful to you.
属下对少君一直都是忠贞不二啊
I mean "loyal to you".
不是 忠 忠心不二
I've planned it all out.
本来都计划得好好的
And I've poisoned a glazed plate.
这毒就下在琉璃盏内
I didn't expect the Third Princess
谁知这三公主心血来潮
to replace all the plates with glazed plates on a whim.
将所有的餐具都换成了琉璃盏
It was similar to the time
就像她之前心血来潮
when she rode a horse
纵马长街一样
on the streets on a whim,
导致计划失败
which sabotaged our plan.
异曲同工啊
Things are changeable.
世事无常
I can't control them.
也非属下能够左右
Please give the people who have erred,
还请少君给犯错的人
especially me,
尤其是我
a chance to make amends.
一个将功补过的机会吧
It's not easy to eat to satiety.
吃顿饱饭真是太不容易
Stop eating if you are full.
吃饱了就别吃了
Medical books say,
药用典籍中有说
"The eggplant is sweet, cold and smooth.
茄味甘性寒 质滑而利
It'll harm pregnant women."
孕妇食之 尤见其害
You can't eat it.
你不能吃
Yes.
是
I'll have a crab then.
那我吃个螃蟹好了
The crab is cold.
螃蟹性凉
It can promote blood circulation and remove blood stasis.
有活血化瘀之功效
You can't eat it.
你也不能吃
You are right.
母亲说得对
Spicy chicken.
辣子鸡
I can eat spicy chicken.
辣子鸡我总能吃
Pregnant women can't eat spicy food.
孕妇不能吃辣的
Who put it on the table?
是谁端上来的
Take it away. Hurry.
撤掉 快
My crab.
我 我螃蟹
Wait. My spicy chicken.
等一下 我辣子鸡
Your Highness.
三 三公主
You... You...
你 你这是
What's wrong with my hand?
我手有什么问题吗
Your... Your...
你这 这
Your gecko cinnabar is still intact.
守宫砂尚在呀
Gecko cinnabar?
守 守宫砂
No way.
不对呀
Chen Qianqian is lustful.
陈芊芊好色成性
How can her gecko cinnabar be intact?
怎么还有守宫砂
I have to get the logic of the screenplay straight.
我得回去捋捋剧本逻辑
Maybe Chen Qianqian is the type of girl who smokes, drinks and whores,
难道陈芊芊抽烟 喝酒 逛花楼
but has a kind heart?
但她是个好姑娘
What a pleasant surprise.
那还真是意外之喜啊
I'd like to know how you got pregnant.
我倒要问你 喜从何来
The gecko cinnabar is intact.
是 这守宫砂还在
So I'm not pregnant.
这 喜从何来
Your Highness, you... you...
三公主 你 你
For a prisoner,
为了一个阶下囚
you lied about something as important as reproduction.
居然将子嗣大事信口拈来
You have failed
你真是辜负了
to meet my expectations of you.
我对你的一番期望
You have off-key behaviors.
你如此的不分轻重
You have disgraced us nobles.
真是罔顾了我贵族颜面
Outrageous.
岂有此理
Truly outrageous.
真是岂有此理
Where is Han Shuo? Han Shuo!
韩烁呢 韩烁
No, mother. Mother.
不是 母亲 母亲
Calm down.
你息怒
Don't blame Han Shuo, mother.
你不要怪韩烁 母亲
Explain the situation, Your Highness.
快解释啊 三公主
What exactly is going on?
这到底是怎么回事
I love Han Shuo.
因为我爱韩烁
I fell in love with him at first sight.
女儿与他一见钟情
And my love for him is deep.
便情深意重
I can't live without Han Shuo.
没有韩烁我就活不了了
I really love him.
我是真的喜欢他
Please let us be together.
你就成全我们吧
Fine.
罢了
If you were sensible,
你要是样样明白
you wouldn't be Chen Qianqian.
你就不是陈芊芊了
you'd better get your man under control.
你最好管好你自己的男人
As long as he doesn't make trouble,
只要他不兴风作浪
I'll spare him.
我饶他一条贱命
Otherwise, I'll punish you along with him.
否则的话我连你一块收拾
I'm full.
我 我吃饱了
I need to go back.
我得先回去了啊
I'll go back.
我先回去了
Go.
下去吧
Take all these things away.
把这些都拿走
Your Majesty.
城主
Don't be too sad.
你不用过分悲伤
These things
这些东西呀
will be of use sooner or later.
迟早用得上
I hope so.
但愿吧
Yes.
好
I'm in a difficult situation.
举步维艰哪
People say it's dangerous to keep a ruler company.
都说伴君如伴虎
I'm around a male ruler and a female ruler.
我身边还一公和一母
I can live with the owner of Huayuan City.
花垣城主也就罢了
But what about Han Shuo?
可这韩烁可怎么办啊
He is like a time bomb.
简直就是一颗定时炸弹
No.
不行
I must push him to Chen Chuchu.
我得把他踢到陈楚楚那边去
When the story ends,
故事推到大结局
I'll be able to go home.
我就可以回家了
But the plot is stuck right now.
可现在剧情卡住了呀
Zi Rui,
梓锐
what is a person who writes screenplays
在你们这个年代
called in this era?
写剧本的人叫什么
What is a screenplay?
何为剧本
It's a story.
就 就是话本
A storyteller?
话本先生
Yes. That's it.
对对对 就这个
How do I call a storyteller?
怎么称呼 说书的
Storytelling, variety drama and lyrics
评书 杂剧 戏子唱词
are all...
皆由
They are all written by storytellers?
皆 皆由话本先生撰写
Brilliant.
厉害
When I think about it,
这怎么说起来
seeing what era this is,
按辈分来讲
they are my predecessors.
还是我祖师爷呢
Your Highness, do you want to hear stories?
三公主 想听故事
No.
不是
I want to have a few aides.
想找几个 幕僚
Your Highness.
三公主
Storytellers.
话本先生
The three of them are the best in Huayuan City.
花垣城三甲
I pay respect to you, Your Highness.
见过公主
Where do you work?
三位先生何处高就啊
I tell stories in a tea house.
小人在茶馆说书
I perform shadow plays under a bridge.
小人在天桥耍皮影
I have my own theater.
小人有自己的戏院
Good.
可以呀
They are divided into several classes.
这还分三六九等呢
It's basically the same as our era.
跟我们那儿也差不多
Take a seat.
三位请坐
I invited you here
这我这今天找三位过来
because I just
是因为我有一件事情
couldn't figure out something.
一直想不明白
I hope you'll enlighten me.
想请三位先生帮我指点迷津
Do tell us.
请讲
I wrote a story.
我写了一个故事
The hero...
这男主角就
The hero
男主角
is this banana.
就是这个香蕉
The heroine
这女主角呢
is this apple.
就是这个苹果
The female supporting role
这女配角
is this orange.
就是这个橙子
The original plot is like this.
这原本呢 应该是
The orange snatches the banana who is getting married.
香蕉被这橙子抢了亲
But on the wedding night,
但是在新婚当晚
the banana murders the orange with poison.
把这橙子给毒死了
Then the banana and the apple...
然后呢 就跟这苹果
The two fruits...
这俩水果 就
No.
不
The two people
这两个人啊
go through
就经过了一系列的
love and hatred.
爱恨情仇之后呢
In the end, they become together.
最终 走到了一起
A regular work.
行活
Nothing interesting.
没什么亮点
It follows a pattern.
按部就班即可
That's right.
可不是吗
But the story is different now.
现在不一样了
The orange
这橙子
doesn't die on the wedding night.
成亲当晚 没死
It survives.
留下来了
A plot twist.
反转
Break the mold.
打破程式
It can be a surprise.
有出乎意料的奇效
I'm good at comedy.
本人擅长喜剧
And it's a trick I often use.
惯用此计
I don't want any plot twist.
不要反转
I don't want any surprise.
不要出乎意料
I just want to create a regular work
我就想做个行活
and match up the apple and the banana.
让这苹果跟香蕉赶紧在一起
Then the orange is an obstacle.
那橙子就是个障碍
I suggest that you
小人建议三公主
untangle the situation,
快刀斩乱麻
and make the complicated plot
化繁
simple.
从简
That's so violent.
这 这么暴力呢
This is a living being, after all.
这 这好歹是一个鲜活的生命
Don't do that.
就能不能别
Your Highness,
公主啊
we storytellers
我们写话本呢
have three techniques.
有三门手艺
The plot rhythm must be steady.
剧情节奏稳
The dramatic conflict must be on point.
戏剧矛盾准
Be ruthless to redundant subplots.
对于多余的支线剧情下手要狠
This orange is obviously redundant.
这橙子明显就是多余的
It has to be removed.
得删
No need to remove it.
不用删
I'm good at tragedy.
小人擅长悲剧
Life and death
话本中多些生死离合
entangled with love and hatred
爱恨纠葛
makes a story interesting.
也好看
No.
不行
That's too simple and crude.
这太简单粗暴了啊
You can find
你们就没有点
a technical means
那种技术手段
to make a detour.
给它稍微这样
Am I right?
迂回一下子嘛 对不对
What's your idea?
那公主有何高见哪
Tell me.
你们说
I'd like to put on a show
若是我单独做一场戏
and make the banana
让这苹果跟香蕉
save the apple
来个英雄救
or make the apple save the banana.
不 或者是美救英雄
What do you think?
怎么样
How are you going
这场戏
to put on this show?
你想怎么做
Are you sure Chuchu will pass by the Music and Dance Academy?
你确定楚楚一定会经过教坊司吗
She definitely will.
肯定会
The Third Lady is here.
三郡主来了
She is a princess, not a lady.
什么郡主 是公主
You have grown so tall.
你长这么高
Looking at you makes my neck hurt.
我看你脖子不疼啊
You are so thin.
你这么瘦
Please ingest more food.
你能不能多吃点
You look like a bamboo pole.
跟个竹竿似的
Your Highness.
三公主
Only your employer,
也就是你们老板
the brat Lin Qi,
林七那个死丫头
fancies men of your kind.
才能看得上你们这种
Lin Qi! Lin Qi!
林七 林七
Young Master.
少君
I'd like to see
我倒要看看
what her plan is.
她葫芦里卖的什么药
Come on.
走
Chen Qianqian, don't you dare go that far.
陈芊芊 你别太过分了
As the richest family in Huayuan City,
我林家身为花垣城首富
my family has served Her Majesty and made provisions from generation to generation.
世代侍奉城主 供奉军饷
Even the Second Princess respects me.
就连二郡主都要给我几分薄面
Don't assume you can make trouble here
你别仗着你是城主的女儿
just because you are Her Majesty's daughter.
就在我这儿撒野
What,
怎么
your men aren't talented enough and you forbid me to criticize them?
你的人才艺不行还不让人说
My men aren't talented enough?
我的人才艺不行
Have you
难不成
found a more talented man
你近日遇到了出类拔萃的
to compete with me?
要与我攀比呀
Sure.
那是自然
Everyone knows I have married
谁不知道我近日
the Young Master of Xuanhu lately.
新抢了玄虎少君啊
What do you mean?
什么意思
Let's have a competition.
要不然我们比试比试
We'll see who the most talented man
我们比花垣城
in Huayuan City is.
才艺最佳的男人是谁
Fine.
比就比
Who is your contestant?
你出谁
Han Shuo is.
出韩烁
Go find Su Mu.
去 把苏沐找来
Yes.
是
Gosh.
天啊
The Third Princess is using Young Master Han as a wager.
三公主居然把韩少君当赌注
She is betting on him.
给押上了
-Han Shuo. -Han Shuo.
韩烁 韩烁
So many people have deserted the streets to see Su Mu here.
万人空巷看苏郎
The Young Master of Xuanhu is going to lose the competition.
这玄虎少君怕是要输喽
In Huayuan City,
在我们花垣城
women make decisions about their households.
一向是女人当家做主
If you dare to defy me,
你若是敢违抗我
I'll divorce you
我就将你休弃
and drive you back to Xuanhu City.
赶回玄虎城
You'll never be able to enter Huayuan City again.
让你不得踏入花垣城半步
Han Shuo, you'd better think it over.
少君 你可得想好了
Young Master.
少君
The Dragon Bone.
龙骨
A little impatience spoils great plans.
小不忍则乱大谋
Chen Qianqian,
陈芊芊
you are pushing me.
你这是在逼我
the Crown Princess of the owner of Xuanhu City
堂堂玄虎城少城主
can't even defeat a musician?
连个乐人都比不过
You...
你
Our Young Master is mighty and masculine.
我们少君威猛阳刚
He is unmatched in this world.
举世无双
That's great.
那最好
Let's welcome Su Mu.
请苏沐
Alright. Alright. No crowd.
好了好了别挤了
Calm down.
都冷静一点
No crowd.
别挤了
Look at me.
快看看我呀
Do you see that?
看见没
He's going to the Third Princess again.
又朝三公主去了
Only the Third Princess can draw him out.
也就三公主能叫动他
Your Highness, we haven't seen each other in a long time.
三公主多日不见
How come you are here
怎么刚成亲
soon after getting married?
就来小人这儿了
Is it because the men of Xuanhu
莫不是玄虎男子
have no grasp of music theories?
不懂乐理
Your Highness.
三公主
When you are free,
您要是有时间
come to the Music and Dance Academy and enjoy music.
就常来教坊司听曲
Alright?
可好啊
So good-looking.
真好看
Why is Chuchu still not here?
楚楚怎么还没来
I don't know.
我不知道
It's so pleasing to the ear.
太好听了也
So euphonious.
真好听
All the men of Huayuan City
咱们花垣城的男人
can play musical instruments and sing songs.
都会弹琴唱曲
Yeah.
就是
What can the men of Xuanhu City do?
玄虎城的男人会什么
They can't do anything.
什么都不会
Fight.
打
Young Master Han is pretty nice.
韩少君也不错啊
Good-looking. So good-looking.
好看 真好看
What a shame.
可惜呀
He has a heart disease
居然患有心疾
that attacks from time to time.
时不时地犯病
I think the Third Princess
我看这三公主
is making things difficult for him on purpose.
就是在刁难人家
It looks like a goddess is scattering flowers.
天女散花一样
Young Master Han is amazing.
韩少君也不错啊
Where is Chuchu?
楚楚呢
I've put on such a show
我搭这么大个戏台子
for her.
就是为等她
Why is she still not here?
她怎么还没有来
If she doesn't show up to defend Han Shuo now,
这她要是再不来帮韩烁出头
I might irritate
这个大魔王
this demon king to death.
可能就要被我活活气死了
Watch out!
小心
How dare you!
放肆
You aimed your sword at Qianqian.
竟敢对芊芊刀剑相向
No, Chuchu. Chuchu.
不 二姐 二姐
Chuchu, you got it wrong.
二姐 你误会了
I forced him to do this.
这是我逼他的
Chuchu.
二姐
You... You are supposed to help him.
你 你应该替他解围
You are supposed to scold me
你应该骂我
and reprimand me.
斥责我呀你
You are supposed to be the beauty who saves the hero.
本来就应该美救英雄
How can you two fight?
怎么还打起来
Young Master! That's the Second Princess!
少君 二郡主啊
I've been told the Second Princess is talented and charming.
久闻二郡主才学兼备 气度不凡
Now I finally see you.
今日一见
I'm honored.
幸会
Han Shuo, please behave yourself.
少君请自重
What are you guys doing?
你们在做什么
Chuchu,
二姐
the Young Master of Xuanhu City
堂堂玄虎城少君
was forced by me to compete with a musician.
我逼他与乐人比试
I'm so mean, right?
是不是很过分
Do you feel like scolding me?
想不想骂我
Do you feel like whipping me?
想不想抽我
It's one thing to take your newly wedded husband
你带自己的新婚夫婿
to the Music and Dance Academy,
来教坊司也就罢了
and it's another thing to make him compete with a musician.
还逼他与乐人比试
Scold me.
骂吧
Then take him to your mansion, so he can recover there.
然后把他带到府中养伤
So, you disrespected her
那你就敢对她无礼
and attempted to assassinate her.
甚至意图行刺
It seems you men of Xuanhu have no idea of virtues
看来你们玄虎的男人不懂夫德
and need education.
需要好好教导
Guards.
来人
Yes.
在
Capture him.
给我把他拿下
No. No.
不 不可
Chuchu, he is Han Shuo. You...
二姐 他可是韩烁
Just a hostage sent from Xuanhu City
不过是玄虎城
to our city for marriage.
派来联姻入赘的质子
I see no reason to stand by.
有何不可
I've been giving you everything
从小到大你想要什么
you want since childhood.
我便都给你
No matter how stubborn Han Shuo is,
韩烁再倔强
I'll tame him for you.
我也要替你驯服
Thank you, I guess.
我可谢谢您嘞
Your Highness, you might as well do it yourself.
二郡主不如自己亲自动手
No. No. No.
完了完了完了
This is messed up.
这是乱套了
The plot isn't developing in the right direction.
剧情不能生推
My hero and heroine
我的男女主角
are supposed to fall in love at first sight.
应该是一见钟情见面
But they are fighting now.
现在他们怎么打起来了
Stop!
停
His clothing has been torn.
衣服都被扯破了
Where are his manners as the Crown Princess?
这哪有一城少主的威仪呀
It's out of control.
玩脱了
Can somebody save me from this situation?
有谁来给我解围啊
Stop.
住手
-Minister Pei. -Minister Pei.
裴司学 裴司学
Minister Pei is so handsome.
裴司学好帅呀
Forget him.
别想了
The Third Princess has been engaged to him since childhood.
三公主从小就跟他定了婚约
Hasn't she married Young Master Han?
她不是跟了韩少君了吗
Young Master Han has a heart disease.
韩少君患有心疾
He can't live for long.
活不了多久
Outrageous.
胡闹
He is the Crown Princess of a City Owner.
堂堂少君
How can we slight him like this?
怎可对他如此怠慢
Finally, someone said the right line.
台词终于有人说了
Pei Heng.
裴恒
This is my favorite role.
这可是我最喜欢的角色
How can we
大庭广众之下
tear Young Master Han's clothing in public?
怎可让韩少君衣冠不整
Yes. Yes. Yes.
对对对
I bullied him and forgot...
是我欺人太甚 罔顾
Forgot about etiquette and rules.
罔顾礼法
I was being unruly and willful.
刁蛮任性
Let's call it a day.
要不然今天就到这儿
Go home, people.
大家都回去吧
Go home.
散了散了散了
Look. The Third Princess really listens to Minister Pei.
看 三公主多听裴司学的话
Her new love and old love.
新欢旧爱
And there is Su Mu.
那儿还有个苏沐呢
Let's go.
走了走了走了
Minister Pei, look at her.
裴司学 你看她
Right after marrying Young Master Han,
刚跟韩少君成了婚
she took him to the Music and Dance Academy for a competition.
就把他带来教坊司比试
How inappropriate.
这成何体统
It's all her idea.
这都是她的主意
Don't blame me.
你可千万别怪我
It's your idea?
是你的主意
Yes, my idea.
我的主意
Han Shuo, don't blame Chuchu.
韩烁 你可千万别怪楚楚
Chuchu, don't blame Han Shuo.
楚楚 你也千万别怪韩烁
Your Highness,
三公主
come with me.
你随我来一下
I need to talk to you.
我有话要对你讲
Deploy the archers.
安排好弓箭手
If Chen Qianqian doesn't
陈芊芊要是今晚
die of arrow wounds tonight,
没有万箭穿心而亡
I will take your life.
我摘下你的狗头
Yes.
属下领命
I didn't like you
我以往不喜欢你
because you were unruly and willful
就是因为你刁蛮任性
and you acted recklessly.
恣意妄为
Since you ignored our engagement
你既然无视我们的婚约
and took the Young Master of Xuanhu to your mansion by force,
强抢玄虎少君入府
you should treat him well.
就应该好好待他
I can't believe you are so stupid
没想到 你冥顽不灵
and have no regard for other people's feelings.
丝毫不顾及他人感受
It's not like that.
不是的
Young Master Han has married into your family in Huayuan City.
韩少君入赘花垣城
He is all alone and helpless.
一个人孤苦伶仃
He has no family and friend.
没有亲人 朋友
His parents are not with him.
父母又不在身边
He doesn't even have anyone to talk to.
连个说话的人都没有
He must be treading on thin ice and every step he takes could lead to danger.
可谓如履薄冰 步步危机
You are
你
too willful.
太过骄纵
I'll ask Her Majesty
明日我会禀明城主
to cancel our engagement tomorrow.
正式取消你我二人婚约
You and Young Master Han...
你与韩少君
Why are you crying?
你哭什么
I'm also alone and helpless.
我也是一个人孤苦伶仃
I have no friend and family.
身边没有朋友 亲人
My parents aren't with me.
父母也不在身边
I don't even have anyone to talk to.
连个说话的人都没有
I'm also treading on thin ice and every step I take could lead to danger.
我也是步步危机 如履薄冰
I just want to go home.
我真的只是太想回家了
It's why I made this unwise decision.
才出此下策的
Pei Heng, stop scolding me.
裴恒 你别骂我了
I like you very much.
我挺喜欢你的
What... what did you say?
你 你说什么
I mean
我的意思是
that I didn't intend to humiliate Han Shuo.
我的本意就没有想要欺辱韩烁
You compared him with a musician at the Music and Dance Academy.
将他与教坊司乐人做比较
You don't think that's humiliation?
还不算欺辱吗
I'm sorry.
对不起嘛
You're... sorry?
对 对不起
I know.
我知道
I made a mistake.
是我错了
You... You are really apologizing?
你 你居然会道歉